<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-01T12:32:12-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/</id><title type="html">Aim4Strength Fitness</title><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Weight Loss New Years Resolutions</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/weight-loss-new-years-resolutions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weight Loss New Years Resolutions" /><published>2017-12-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/weight-loss-new-years-resolutions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/weight-loss-new-years-resolutions/">&lt;p&gt;So many diets, so little time….Weight loss new years resolutions.  It&amp;rsquo;s almost a cliche, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? I know, because I used to do them every year, and still look forward to a new start, if I am to be completely honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with every new start you have done, how many times have you failed?  I know I have failed many New Years Resolutions over the years.  Let me tell you why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because lasting change is hard to do &lt;u&gt;mic drop&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by this is that we go into a new years resolution with a ton of motivation and many dreams of reaching our goals—which is especially true for weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has become the norm to start a diet on January 1st of every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its like you are a freak of nature if you don’t have a New Years resolution every year…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does that mean you should not make any New Years resolutions?  I mean, do you even keep them beyond March?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I say you &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; make New Year’s Resolutions.  I am sure that surprises you, but I am all for getting hyped for a new start and a new year.  I love the way it makes me feel, and I love that I get to start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Caveat: you will have some bumps in the road.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what do you do?  How do you navigate January’s “new year, new you” campaign?  How can you make it last for the_ whole_ year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get hyped all you want, but have a plan for when you screw up.  A plan is super important because you will fail and get all depressed and fall into a quart of Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s of you don’t have some sort of a strategy.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, lets say you decided to start a type of eating program, like a low carb high fat diet, or a lower calorie diet; whatever it may be.  Its day 35, and you want to throw a tantrum because you want chocolate, dammit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you imbibe.  You eat so much, that you look 8 months pregnant.  Now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where your exit plan comes into play—You ate the chocolate.  Smile about it.  You ate it, I hope you enjoyed it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you forgive yourself and move on.  You go right back to the plan you were doing.  Thats right, you got it out of your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Don’t make it weird.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move on, get over it, and stop obsessing about how you screwed up.  What is done is done, its in the past. just like Rafiki says…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t start something you KNOW you can’t do. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have all seen those people that are 400 pounds go to the gym, practically kill themselves with working out, and in a few days are in so much pain and suffering they feel like dying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I have done this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we all have.  However, it doesn’t make you like exercise or dieting at all,  it doesn’t make it enjoyable and its something that you most likely cannot sustain for any length of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a change that can be lasting and fit into your lifestyle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I am not letting you off the hook.  Make no mistake, you will have to change in order to….Change. Duh. It&amp;rsquo;s the Law of thermodynamics, or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story time….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried to lose weight since I was 5.  I was fat all of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would go on these crazy diets like the cabbage soup diet, the grapefruit diet and exercise so hard that I couldn’t walk the next day.  I could stay only stay on a diet or exercise program for only 20 days, tops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after I had given up dieting, lost all hope of losing weight, a little work place contest came into my life.  I knew if I was to win this contest I had to make some major changes, but changes that could fit into my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest was 6 months long, so doing a 20 day fast wasn’t gonna cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to make changes that I knew I could sustain for a 6 month period of time.  Long story short, that was 8 years ago.  I have kept off 160 pounds. Well, ok, more like 152 because of Christmas goodies…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do something you like.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, another duh moment. You are going to be doing this for the long haul, so why punish yourself by eating kale all day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to do things that you aren’t your jam, that is true.  However, why torture yourself all the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love ice-cream.  I love sweets.  I make sure they are in my life in one fashion or another, otherwise life isn’t worth it.  I know, it sounds so dramatic, but I AM pretty passionate about my chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I eat low cal versions of it.  For instance, if I want ice cream I eat Arctic Zero (150 cals a pint) or some other low calorie version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I want chocolate.  I have a ton of chocolate protein powder that I make all kinds of stuff with (MTS Whey is my fav—you can click on the link &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigerfitness.com&quot;&gt;www.tigerfitness.com&lt;/a&gt; to get you some!) And that also completes my protein needs nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love lifting heavy.  I love yoga, and doing flexibility work, so I do that.  I try new stuff to add to my repertoire. If I like moving in ways I love, then it will be easier to get my ass to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expect people to be negative.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I said it.  The people in your life that love you the most may root for you at first, but when you start to change your ways for a period of time, you will get lots of pushback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t mean that don’t love you, it means they don’t like being affected, even if it is  collaterally with change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another story time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I had lost all of my weight and kept it off for a few years.  My husband was Mr. Negative Nancy.  He hated that I lost my weight, and even though he tried to be supportive at times, he hated that I changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was because I changed his life, not just mine.  I changed our movie dates that were surrounded by food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed our dinner dates now that I watched my weight.  I changed what we did for fun, because I wanted to be more active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collateral changes may not be welcomed by people who are closest to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive them, move on, and &lt;u&gt;do you, boo.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, you are changing yourself for the better, and you have to tell them that.  The biggest advice I can give you is to continue on your journey; be empathetic to their needs, but don’t give in to the negativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt; Believe me, its hard. &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to an understanding with my husband that works well for us now.  I exercise my face off when he is not home or if he is running errands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t ask anymore for him to go with me—it&amp;rsquo;s not his thing-and thats cool, because it IS mine.  He doesn’t stop me from doing it, and I don’t rag at him for not doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still go out for dinner, and I work it out—I look up stuff online before we go so I know what I can have.  I wish I could say I don’t plan anymore, but I do, and will likely do so for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So to wrap it up…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have humongous, crazy, weirdo goals.  Make them big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do the whole New Years’ resolution thing—its awesome that you are motivated by the new year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realize that motivation fades and difficulties often accompany the work it takes to reach your goal, so have a plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When doing the steps it takes to get to your goal, do things that are not so out of the realm for you.  Baby steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t deviate from your goal, and don’t let others derail you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you screw up, get back on the wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these things are something you can completely do with little tweaks to your day to day life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You got this!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">So many diets, so little time….Weight loss new years resolutions.  It&amp;rsquo;s almost a cliche, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? I know, because I used to do them every year, and still look forward to a new start, if I am to be completely honest.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574377/new-years-resolutions.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Stop Being a Poser</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/how-to-stop-being-a-poser-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Stop Being a Poser" /><published>2017-12-26T18:44:11-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-26T18:44:11-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/how-to-stop-being-a-poser-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/how-to-stop-being-a-poser-3/">&lt;p&gt;Are You a Poser?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I have lost a lot of weight, and I have kept it off.  I should feel all good about myself, right?  Well, actually I feel like a total poser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days I feel like I am living a lie and that everyone will know that I am really fat inside. They will find out that &lt;u&gt;shocker&lt;/u&gt; I still have issues with food…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I am hear to tell you that you will likely always have that voice in your head when you reach your goal—the one that screams at you that you’re an imposter and you really don’t know what you’re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That voice in your head is a total a-hole&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I suffer through that voice on a daily basis.  If I listen to the voice, it gets stronger, but when I don’t its in the background, almost like white noise, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought for a long time that I was just on the crazy train-I mean only people with auditory hallucinations hear voices, right?  Um, nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I freaking love Mel Robbins, She is able to explain that voice inside your head better than anyone I have ever read.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.melrobbins.com&quot;&gt;www.melrobbins.com&lt;/a&gt;.  She talks about the “imposter” syndrome and how to combat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ever Heard of a Little Thing Called Neuroplasticity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not neuroscience 101, promise….however, this does tie in with the imposter theme here, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, neuroplasticity is defined as “lasting change to the brain throughout an individual&amp;rsquo;s life course. “  This is per Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you may be an old dog, but you &lt;u&gt;can&lt;/u&gt; learn new tricks.  How that is applicable with the voice is very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you can &lt;u&gt;make&lt;/u&gt; new neural connections and you can_ break_ neural connections, too.  Lets say you have been fat all your life, and now, over the course of years have lost that weight and kept it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But you have made new connections and habits, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That voice in your head is like the remnant factor of your old self (which had a habit of being a dick to you) and that connection is still there.  It may be weak, but its still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence hearing that voice in your head that tells you that you don’t deserve to do well and basically you suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, even though we made new connections, the old ones may still be present.  Weak, but still present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some of my own tips to decrease the imposter syndrome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop listening to that voice.  Like, go deaf to that horrid little naysayer &lt;u&gt;right this very minute!&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easier said than done.  I still have that vixen telling me that I suck on a daily basis, and I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;have to really concentrate on drowning her out either with another thought or just turn up my&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your plan and stick to it.  If you don’t, she will get louder, call you all kinds of names, and try to derail your progress that you have made.  If I don’t write things down, I will likely become paralyzed to the she-devil voice and listen to it.  She loves when I am paralyzed with fear, and she gets louder.  I feel like I am back in 6th grade being tormented by a bully….&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you fail, fall off the wagon, screw up, know that it is temporary.  If you are trying to become something better in your life, that voice will get louder, screaming that you are a big fat poser.  You have to remember that she is your insecurity talking.  She is still you, just with a fouler mouth and a ton more fears.  Be kind to her, but firm.  Drown her out kindly.  If you listen to her, don’t get pissed at yourself.  Just take a deep breath and regroup.  Then, shut that biotch down and ignore her.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poser thing can happen over many years and have lots of layers-like an onion.  You try to look and act smart in math class, but you cant add 2+4 and get the right answer.  Poser!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do that long enough, you know deep down that you are an imposter, but your mom expects you to make an “A” in the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you work hard and you finally have bugged your teacher so much that he gave you an “A” in the class because you have worked hard, even progressed on something you didn’t think you could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, that voice screams how you are a faker, that you will be found out and exposed for the imposter you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same with anything you are striving to do well at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to achieve a skill that you didn’t possess before, and arrive at achieving the skill, you almost feel like someone will come along and tell you that you really don’t know what you are doing, that you are a poser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time this voice will get harder to hear.  The poser thing stays with you for a long time only if you listen to the voice in your head that keeps that connection alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, stop.  Regroup, stop listening to that voice and make a plan.  All of these will help drown out the voice and hopefully you will become deaf to her ramblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got this!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Are You a Poser?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574374/dont-be-afraid-of-change.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How I lost 160 Pounds in a Little Over a Year and a Half</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/lost-160-pounds-little-year-half/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I lost 160 Pounds in a Little Over a Year and a Half" /><published>2017-12-14T05:33:59-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-14T05:33:59-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/lost-160-pounds-little-year-half</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/lost-160-pounds-little-year-half/">&lt;p&gt;Yes, folks, it can be done, I am living proof.  You &lt;u&gt;can&lt;/u&gt; lose weight over 40.  Hell, you can lose weight at &lt;u&gt;any age.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been an overweight person my whole life.  Like, for real.  I was a fat kid, a fat teen and a fat adult.  At my largest I was 300 pounds, a size 28 and a 5 x in tops.  I was a big girl, for sure…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are overweight, you probably can feel my pain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was worried about all kinds of things—will I be able to fit in that booth at the restaurant, will I be able to get a seat belt extender for the plane, the list goes on….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not only annoying, but downright embarrassing.  I remember going into the store to buy groceries and a little blue-haired lady came up to me and indignantly said, “I don’t think you need these cookies.” She promptly took them out of my basket.  I was beyond embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to crawl in a hole and never come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really plodded through life &lt;u&gt;knowing&lt;/u&gt; that I would never be a “normal-sized” person.  There was no hoping anymore; I lost that a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered a workplace contest.  For money.  Because….I really liked money.  I expected to lose weight and gain it right back; however, the contest was for an extended period of time-6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never done a weight loss challenge for that amount of time.  I was worried about how I was going to do and knew that I needed more than a diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I needed a plan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I set my brain afire with a plan on how to lose weight in order to win that money.  Yes, I knew how to get it off fast, but how do I do it so it will stay off for 6 months?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was to decide how I was going to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What diet to choose was the bane of my existence for many years.  I had a hard time eating anything other than fast food and chocolate.  How the hell was I going to do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I picked a plan I felt I could stick to.&lt;/strong&gt;  I started Weight Watchers.  They have an excellent program that gives you some freedom to pick what you want to eat and count your points. I liked that they had guidelines, meetings and educational info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that done, I knew I also needed something to get me moving—and I am not talking about changing the channel or walking to the refrigerator either.  I had to get serious and get serious fast…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I like to do as far as exercise? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duh-who likes to exercise?  Ewww.  I really had to think long and hard about this.  I had always wanted to be a runner in school, but sucked at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything else was pretty intimidating because it had me going into a gym where I wasn’t too sure I could  even fit into the machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought long and hard, and felt this was my best option.  I knew I would have to walk first, and that was a lot less intimidating then gym work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I started to exercise with a local running group.&lt;/strong&gt; The accountability was important to me, because obviously I had issues with it and knew that for the first few months I needed someone to push me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started walking at first, and let me tell you, (no filter) it was absolutely horrid my first day.  I walked 5 miles and thought I was going to die.  But I didn’t die, and I kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I did 1 full marathon and more than 25 half-marathons during my running journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now what?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, the next thing I did was to become the town cryer.  I told everyone about this contest.  I am talking &lt;u&gt;everyone.&lt;/u&gt; From my hairdresser, to my family to the guy with the lazy eye at the grocery store-I told them all in detail what I had to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to, believe me, I wanted to keep it secret, because if I failed, there would be no one staring and me thinking I was a big fat loser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure you are saying to yourself, ok, thats all well and good, but how did you &lt;u&gt;stay&lt;/u&gt; on it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you, that was the biggest challenge for me and for anyone that has started a diet plan or an exercise plan-how in the hell do you stay on it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The biggest thing I did besides the obvious diet and exercise changes was being ok with failure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure you are saying to yourself, come on, you have got to be kidding me—be ok with failure?  Umm, I want to be successful, why in the world are you talking about failing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However,  failure is thing for me. Failing made me the way I was and I didn’t want to be the way I was—at least I didn’t for a 6 month period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I also knew myself well.  I knew that failure was gonna happen.  I mean, come on, its 6 months!  That is a long time to go without cake, if you know what I am saying…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, I created the 49/51% rule.&lt;/strong&gt; This rule has absolutely, unequivocally saved my live and was the defining factor in &lt;u&gt;keeping my weight off&lt;/u&gt;. Here is the deal.  I liked that I had accountability in the Weight Watchers group and my running group, but I knew at some point failure would happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also knew how I have reacted to failure in the past—I dove head first into a chocolate cake, thats how I reacted.  So, the 49/51 % rule was like a built-in fail-safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, if I knew I was going to fail and expected it and planned for it, then it wouldn’t be as disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, for 4 days out of the week I was super strict on the Weight Watchers plan, and 3 days out of the week, well, not so much.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, don’t get me wrong—I didn’t eat a whole cake every day on the three days I was “off plan.”  I actually ate pretty close to what I ate in the days I was on; with one caveat—if we were going out or I was craving something, I ate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I craved chips, I had some.  Some days I had half the bag, and some days only a few.  I still constrained myself, but gave myself more leeway on those three days than I did on the 4 days when I was super strict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I hit plateaus.  Yes, I got frustrated and wanted to quit at least once a week.  But I was losing weight at a steady pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t come off as fast as it would have if I was on a fad diet, and in my mind, that was frustrating, but I soldiered on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a year and a half, I stepped on the scale, and to my delight I was 138 pounds.  I was over the moon about it.  I will leave the next chapter of my journey to my next blog post….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lets recap, shall we?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick a “diet plan” you can do and doesn’t leave you in binge mode.  Then, pick an exercise you like and have always wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once those are done, tell everyone, even the guy with the lazy eye at the grocery store.  The last and most important part—realize you will fail and implement a way to mitigate how you feel about failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be totally consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viola, weight loss accomplished!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="diet" /><category term="exercise" /><category term="failure" /><category term="How I lost 160 Pounds in a Little Over a Year" /><category term="lose weight" /><category term="plan" /><summary type="html">Yes, folks, it can be done, I am living proof.  You can lose weight over 40.  Hell, you can lose weight at any age.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574375/how-I-lost-160-lbs.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Self Sabotage and American Ninja Warrior</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/self-sabotage-american-ninja-warrior/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self Sabotage and American Ninja Warrior" /><published>2017-12-10T06:48:57-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-10T06:48:57-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/self-sabotage-american-ninja-warrior</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/self-sabotage-american-ninja-warrior/">&lt;p&gt;Holy cow!  Another week down and another week closer to getting that American Ninja Warrior application in….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I am humming with excitement and all consuming terror at the thought of even turning in my application.  It&amp;rsquo;s likely nothing will come of it, but……what if something does?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this is almost as big as losing weight.  It feels like a goal that is totally outside my realm of achieve and I am having a hard time even picturing myself doing something so crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the same way that day I gave my money to be in a work place competition to win money.  I was totally panic-stricken.  The second I handed over my mulah, I wanted to eat my face off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self Sabotage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh come on—you guys have all done it.  You proclaim your going to get fit and healthy, and then you see a Popeyes and you just cant help diving face deep into some fried chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have set ourselves up for failure at one time or another.  I have done this all my life and really am an expert at it.  In fact, I can self sabotage without even thinking about it, because I am so fearful about how to get to my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big goals, goals outside of our comfort zone or even little goals that freak you out can have you diving into a pint of  Ben&amp;amp;Jerry’s ice cream-and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be weight related goals, fitness goals or health goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be that you are doing a scary new project at work.  For me, meeting people I don&amp;rsquo;t know makes me sick to my stomach and want to run crying to the nearest Carl’s Jr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips that help me when I am doing something really scary and want to ruin my own progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.  Remember why you are doing what you are doing.  Write it down, talk to people about it, sing it to the world.  You will hate yourself for opening your big fat mouth, but it will make you disinclined to screw your own self over.  Its kind of a form of punishment as you are publicly shaming yourself if you don&amp;rsquo;t do that scary thing, but hey, it works most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.  Make a plan.  This one is very important.  You have to have a plan of attack.  This alleviates some stress and helps you to just “getter done.” Sometimes its just easier to follow a written plan that you or someone else made up to alleviate pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.  It&amp;rsquo;s ok to be scared shitless.  Give yourself a break.  Allow yourself to feel that fear, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it take over your whole life so you are paralyzed by it.  A little fear gives you a push in the right direction, being taken over by fear makes you stop in your tracks and basically holds you back from achieving your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.  Be self aware.  You may not even know that you are super afraid.  You may be like me and have a tendency to actually live life fearfully and in order to realize that you are being a cry baby, you actually have to look inward and talk to yourself about your fears daily.  Yes, I am the weirdo at the store that is muttering under her breath like I have an imaginary friend—“you can do it, Julie, don&amp;rsquo;t be such a wuss, Julie, stop being a cry baby pee-pee pants, Julie….”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been fighting the rising fear ever since I said I was going to tryout for ANW.  I have been thwarting myself through diet by eating too much, I have been a bit paralyzed with fear and not doing what I know it will take in order to get to the next level physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here is where the buck stops.  I am putting my money where my mouth is and writing this to call myself out.  I have written out a plan of things to accomplish so that I can just rely on that and not think too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for all you failures, self saboteurs and “losers” out there—We have each others back.  We can change anything in our lives we want to, even do things that you may think are beyond your reach if we &lt;u&gt;believe.&lt;/u&gt; We can do all this stuff together, and help each other be the best selves we can be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="American ninja warrior" /><category term="fear" /><category term="goals" /><category term="plan" /><category term="self aware" /><category term="self sabotage" /><category term="Self sabotage and American Ninja Warrior" /><summary type="html">Holy cow!  Another week down and another week closer to getting that American Ninja Warrior application in….</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574379/american-ninja-warrior.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Mitigate the Holiday 15</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/mitigate-holiday-15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Mitigate the Holiday 15" /><published>2017-12-05T08:19:23-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-05T08:19:23-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/mitigate-holiday-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/mitigate-holiday-15/">&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it funny how media switches from diet advice to “eat all things” during the Holidays?  I find it quite ironic how there is no happy medium between these things; you should be starving yourself with celery during the summertime and then gain at least 15 pounds during the holidays or you aren’t doing it up right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been on that rollercoaster for years, and to be completely transparent, still have a tendency to continue on that wild ride.  The temptations abound and it is really hard to say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy hell, everyone and their mother posted stuff on National Cookie Day a couple of days ago, and I couldn’t stop salivating.  Pavlov’s dog has nothing on me….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do during this time of year?  Go out and get a Tofurkey to not eat too much fat and protein during Christmas dinner?  Get sugar free Chocolate for Uncle Bobs stocking because he’s a horrible diabetic_ and_ a chocoholic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips I use that can mitigate the “holiday 15.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make a plan.  I know I wont be too popular with this tip, but its my top tip for mitigating the holiday weight gain.  Make a plan.  Write it down.  Stick to it.  If you fall off that plan, forgive yourself and move on—dont make it a slippery slope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eat like you normally do.  I know.  You want me to tell you to eat all the cake.  I would like that, too, but its not feasible.  When I say eat normally, I mean eat the way you always do with a slight caveat—if you know you are going to a party that has tons of stuff, eat light that day, and at night try_ everything_.  Don’t gorge yourself, though.  Christmas and parties are only isolated days, so pick like 2 days during that week that you will be participating in eating crap.  Adjust your calories or your macros and guestmate.  Don’t weigh the next day, either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Know that willower is dumb.  &lt;u&gt;What?&lt;/u&gt; I don’t believe in willpower.  I am a strong woman who can do anything I set my mind to, but could never lose weight. It means that I just didn’t know how to make my weight loss happen step by step.  Willpower is a word (at least to me) that means only a select few can have it, and the rest of us don’t have what it takes.  Such BS!   I believe that it is habit that creates success, not willpower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drink a ton.  Not alcohol—I meant water.  Water is totally the bane of my existence, and if I never had to drink it again, I wouldn’t.  I don’t like it.  With that being said, if I get desperate enough in a bad situation, I will drink it because I want to not eat all things cake related.  Well, I do, but I don’t want to feel horrible about myself because I got chocolate wasted the night before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember what the holidays are about.  Hint-its not &lt;u&gt;all&lt;/u&gt; about food.  I get that you want to make something special for your family, but it doesn’t have to be crap food. Look online-they have healthy choices for every type of food, and Grandma and Grandpa or Uncle Joe don’t have to know what you’re doing in the kitchen.  Some of that stuff is really good and you can’t taste the difference, and some of it you can.  Experiment.  Laugh about it, have fun doing it.  Get the kids involved in making something different this year.  If you come at it like you are doing it for fun or a challenge, you may have buy in from the fam bam.  If you come at it like, “we are so unhealthy, we are going to make stuff that is healthier and doesn’t taste as good,” you may have a Christmas mutany on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it.  Its hard to do, don’t get me wrong, but it can be done.  Willpower has nothing to do with it.  Planning, preparing and action has &lt;u&gt;everything&lt;/u&gt; to do with it, though.  Even then, you may find that you are still having a hard time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know that most of America is in the same boat as you are.  The key is, to just get back to it. You may gain a few pounds, but I can guarantee it will be less that what it was last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember what Christmas is about—family, love and giving, not stuffing your face, gaining a ton of weight and hating yourself for it.  You got this!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="Christmas" /><category term="dieting tips" /><category term="Holiday weight gain" /><category term="how to mitigate holiday weight gain" /><category term="willpower" /><summary type="html">Isn’t it funny how media switches from diet advice to “eat all things” during the Holidays?  I find it quite ironic how there is no happy medium between these things; you should be starving yourself with celery during the summertime and then gain at least 15 pounds during the holidays or you aren’t doing it up right.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574379/keep-call-you-are-a-badass.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jumping into “American Ninja Warrior”</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/jumping-into-anw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jumping into &quot;American Ninja Warrior&quot;" /><published>2017-12-01T07:53:44-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T07:53:44-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/jumping-into-anw</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/12/jumping-into-anw/">&lt;p&gt;‘Merica….Ninja Warrior, That Is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, its that time of year where American Ninja Warrior starts to search for the most talented people out there to go to Mt Midoriyama.  Well, search no further.  I am here, friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the thought of going through a whole course and being such a total boss that when Kristine Leahy asks me how I did it, I am going to say, “it was really no biggie, Kristine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If age and gas were the defining factor, I would win hands down, no question about it. Just because I am pushing 50 and have been morbidly obese for 75% of my life doesn’t mean I can’t do tryouts. I mean, man, I got a shelf life here. I could need CPR and a whole lot of shocks if I wait much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have decided to apply, I am kind of freaking out.  Like ‘going into the bathroom and hyperventilating for a few minutes before trying to look all put together’ freaking out.…  How the heck am I even going to accomplish this?  What kinds of workouts will I be doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first order of business is to wrap my head around what I will be asked to do.  Sounds dumb, right?  I mean, duh, you have seen ANW, so you know what is expected of you…..wrong. The jumping spider looks easy, but to do it? Fear of falling freaks me out, and I know that its more in my head than it is I can’t do something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My workouts will consist of pull-ups. Followed by pull-ups.  Spattered with a little jumping pull-ups for a finisher.  What I am trying to say is that I will be doing a ton of pull-ups.  Most of the show the contestants are hanging on to small ledges, doorknobs and ropes.  I will need superb grip strength, insane upper body strength and high intensity training for sure….Oh crap, I am in trouble….&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keep it fun.  I will have to remind myself of this daily. I like to win.  I like to hang upside down.  I like challenging myself.  Usually, fun is not on the top of my list, because I let all the other things cloud this fundamental rule.  I am the kind of person if you tell me I can’t, I will find a way, especially if its important to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take from different types of sports/genres of fitness.  Rock climbing, Gymnastics, Parkour, Calisthenics—they all have something that can be used on the ANW course.  The common theme is upper body strength and high intensity training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Train smarter not harder.  Short bouts of HIIT with monkey bar work, dead hangs, pull ups, balance work and ab work with strength training sprinkled in.  I will be doing 3 upper body days and 2 lower body days.  I will have some HIIT every day that I work out, and it will be used as a superset to every exercise.  This is so that I can get my heart up to snuff and because I am slow at everything I do.  I am going to try to tolerate this workout regime and want to be in the gym no longer than 1.5 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diet.  Oh. My. Gosh. This will be hands down the hardest.  I have a coach for bodybuilding and am eating to those goals…..well, I am trying, anyways.  I will have to lose weight so those will possibly need to be changed.  Right now I eat a good deal of protein, and will still keep doing that.  I also eat a good deal of carbs, which I will need for high intensity training.  I guess I will need to reign it in so that I can do my best.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thats it.  I would love for you to tell me what YOU think I should do that would make me more prepared for this.  I have done a lot of reading on the subject, but there is so much out there, I just feel overwhelmed.  I picked the very things that I feel like you need on the course.  Some things are just plain scary, jumping being one of them.  I am old, hence the fear of falling and breaking a hip is a totally real fear.  Also, I am trying out an ANW gym in Los Angeles.  I have a call in to them to see if they would be willing to host me and a few friends to try and get acquainted with some basic ANW things on the course—the warped wall being one of them as well as the salmon ladder. I will be doing weekly updates on training and what is working versus what is not working-wish me luck!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="aim4strength fitness" /><category term="American ninja warrior" /><category term="diet" /><category term="jumping" /><category term="jumping spider" /><category term="jumpingintoamericanninjawarrior" /><category term="ninja" /><category term="obese" /><category term="training" /><category term="warrior" /><category term="workout" /><summary type="html">‘Merica….Ninja Warrior, That Is.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574377/american-ninja-warrior-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Women Loathe Themselves</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/11/why-women-loathe-themselves/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Women Loathe Themselves" /><published>2017-11-26T19:53:45-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-26T19:53:45-08:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/11/why-women-loathe-themselves</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2017/11/why-women-loathe-themselves/">&lt;p&gt;I was asking my husband what subject I should write about for my blog.  His answer took me by surprise.  “Write about why women hate themselves and men don’t.”  “We don’t hate ourselves,” I said, my voice an octave higher.  “See, you even get defensive over it.  You women hate yourselves.  You will never catch a man getting all emotional with a few lines on his face or a beer gut. We just don’t think like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He may be right.  It might be my imagination, but I think that women are targeted more through marketing and the media to look, act and feel a certain way.  I mean, geez, just look at TV ads—most are targeted to us about our hair, face, skin and weight.  Men?  Well, they get cool commercials like Tums.  Its always a guy that ate that pizza and now is paying for it.  Or what about this one—Enzyte—we all know carefree “Bob” who waves at his neighbors and has a catchy tune to his male enhancement advertisement.  Come to think of it, thats my husbands ring tone….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I really had to think about it.  Yes, I guess I am a little defensive about it.  Maybe he is right about women not ever being satisfied with themselves.  I mean, if you get a room full of women together, they usually end up talking about their hair, skin, or body in some way and its usually negative in nature.  If they are menopausal like myself, they are talking about facial hair, the hormone pellet and how many things are going south forever and not just for the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How in the world can we change our way of thinking, then,  to become more satisfied with ourselves?  What I propose is radical and over the top.  Serious, life changing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop watching TV.  Yup.  Turn off that boob tube.  If you have to, get it out of the room.  In truth, you are actually being brainwashed.  I know, a little extreme.  But is it?  Marketers know that if you hear an ad the first time, its likely not going to phase you.  The 330th  time you hear it,  though, may compulsively call you to buy their product or service. Everyone is susceptible to that, man or woman.  However, I believe that the bulk of products (well, maybe not Enzyte) are being targeted toward women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delete Instagram and Facebook.  Another crazy, over the top thing to do.  However-I can tell you what I do on instagram.  I look at other girls.  No, not in a sleazy way. I do it to compare myself.  I like this girls butt.  I want to have so-in-so’s legs.  What do they eat in a day?  Why does my life suck compared to theirs?  I really don’t see dudes doing that.  If my husband had all these other good-looking men on his instagram and said “hey, do you think I could look like him if I go to the gym more?”  It would totally creep me out.  I do that to him all the time, though. Now, I am not talking forever.  Just a short time.  Maybe a week, maybe a month.  A break may be needed especially if you take an hour or two out of your day just to see other women doing  duck-lipped selfies and sticking their amazing booties out for all the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you think of a negative comment to say to yourself, stop.  Think about how you are bombarded every day with marketing ads that tell you that you aren’t good enough, pretty enough or smart enough.  Just be kind to yourself.  How about you tell yourself something nice?  Something like, “I have a lovely nose.”  Then &lt;u&gt;stop&lt;/u&gt; there.  Don’t say “I have a lovely nose, its way better than Marthas.”  That is a comparison.  Also, its kind of mean.  So stop comparing and stop being mean, especially to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hang with people that care about you, not what you look like or what you have. Yup. For years I hung out with takers, people who made me feel dirty and crappy about myself. They sucked me dry and made me feel like i wasn’t worth much. This happened especially when I was at my top weight of 300 pounds.  I have to say, the fault was mine.  I felt like I was nothing, so I was ok with being treated like I was nothing.  Had I thought higher of myself, then I certainly wouldn’t have wasted my time on people that didn’t have my best interest at heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wake up and think of 3 things you are grateful for.  Like, &lt;u&gt;every single day.&lt;/u&gt; Sometimes, it can be hard, especially if you are the “glass half empty” kind of gal.  Its amazing how far this seemingly stupid step can be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes me sad that I spent a better part of my life trying to please others. I do believe we place too much value on what we see through the media—because we all know Big Boob Barbie who lives in a beach house in Malibu is the happiest person in the world and has an amazing life—until breaking news finds her broke, living the homeless life in LA with a slight meth habit she developed living the good life in Malibu.  So, value YOU.  You are unique.  You are cool, weird, quirky or some other adjective that can be inserted to suit what makes up…well, &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt;.  Don&amp;rsquo;t be self-loathing, because the one person that should be in your corner all the time is &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="Enzyte" /><category term="Media" /><category term="Self Loathing" /><category term="Weight loss" /><category term="Women" /><summary type="html">I was asking my husband what subject I should write about for my blog.  His answer took me by surprise.  “Write about why women hate themselves and men don’t.”  “We don’t hate ourselves,” I said, my voice an octave higher.  “See, you even get defensive over it.  You women hate yourselves.  You will never catch a man getting all emotional with a few lines on his face or a beer gut. We just don’t think like that.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574378/woman-exercising.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I stopped binge eating…or did I?</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/i-stopped-binge-eatingor-did-i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I stopped binge eating…or did I?" /><published>2016-08-10T17:44:06-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T17:44:06-07:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/i-stopped-binge-eatingor-did-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/i-stopped-binge-eatingor-did-i/">&lt;p&gt;You probably think that since I have lost 160+ pounds that I have the food thing figured out, right? I mean, how can you lose that much weight without exercising your face off and eating all organic, whole foods you can get from your own back yard? In fact, when I go places with friends, they offer me cupcakes (OMG I absolutely LOVE cake) and say “well, since your thin now, you can eat that” or my personal favorite, “don’t be so militant, you only live once!”. WRONG!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I am not saying I don&amp;rsquo;t eat those things every now and then, but it’s pretty rare. I am 6 years out from losing this weight, and I am still a zealot when it comes to tracking my food and logging everything that passes by my lips. Hell, I have nightmares when I think I forgot something in my logging app—yes, obsessive behavior at its finest! Most will scoff and think who wants to be on a diet for the rest of their life or that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a balanced life. Guess what? I don’t! I have big food issues—you don&amp;rsquo;t balloon to 300 pounds for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My vice is binge eating. I would love to say binge eating is awful, terrible and that I hate it. Truth be told, I feel absolutely amazing and satisfied when doing it. Afterwards, I feel guilt and shame, but honestly I feel like a million bucks physically. I know I am supposed to feel crappy after eating a whole cake or pizza, but physically I don’t. My body loves chocolate layer cake and feels the happiest when a whole cake is in my belly. Mentally, though, it is a horrible cycle of guilt and shame, then anger at yourself for doing the same thing you promised yourself you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do time and time again. Do not misconstrue what I am saying: it is not ok to binge eat. It comes with a whole host of mental mind games like guilt, shame, anger and inequity. Most of us binge to forget any problems or feelings that we don&amp;rsquo;t want to face. This is no bueno. But let’s call a spade a spade—people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it if it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel good, and lots of people do it, otherwise we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have a whole country full of fat people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there hope? Of course there is. I have to say, just because I lost the weight doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I don&amp;rsquo;t still have food issues. Food is my drug and that will never go away. And like a drug addict, I have to face this daily, acknowledging that I have the power to change it and forgive myself when I fall off the wagon. Oh and believe me, I have fallen off the wagon too many times to count. We are not perfect beings and your habits and chemical makeup are still going to be ingrained in you even if it’s to a lesser degree. Cake is still delicious, and I can still eat like a truck driver on steroids. I know I have a huge problem when I go to the cheesecake factory with friends and finish all of their food that they are too full to eat. (food rookies…!) Unlike my friends, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a stop button. I am like a goat who would eat the shirt off its owner if he could get a hold of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you stop binging? Before losing the weight, every diet plan or every exercise plan I approached with a type A attitude. I was either going to do it, or I wasn’t. If I fell off the wagon, I said screw it, I am going to eat since I already messed up. I had pretty much given diets up by the age of 41, and just accepted the fact that I was going to be a fat with lots of health issues for the rest of my life. However, the weight loss contest we did at work saved me. I was focused on something other than weight. I knew how to get from point A to point B if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t weight loss related. I wanted to win money. Plain and simple. End goal—WIN. I figured after the contest I would gain it all back anyways, so I went into it with that mindset. I ate “around” my food issues. I knew I would binge—duh, no secret since that is what I have always done. So, I implemented my 49/51% rule. I had to eat healthy 51% of the time. Over 50% made me a success, so I knew I would be successful if I hit 51%. I built in binging into my diet—I know, another “no no” in the health and fitness world. Once I knew that I could be 51% successful, the pressure to be perfect dissipated and I actually binged less.  Today, I would have to say I am about 70% successful and 30% binger. I still have issues with perfection and fear of failure, but I do weird stuff for that I will talk about another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in closing, I hope you realize that fear and self-loathing does nothing but keep you stuck in a vicious circle that keeps you stagnant. You CAN lose weight if you are a binger—it absolutely can be done, but you have to change your mindset and your ideas of what success is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">You probably think that since I have lost 160+ pounds that I have the food thing figured out, right? I mean, how can you lose that much weight without exercising your face off and eating all organic, whole foods you can get from your own back yard? In fact, when I go places with friends, they offer me cupcakes (OMG I absolutely LOVE cake) and say “well, since your thin now, you can eat that” or my personal favorite, “don’t be so militant, you only live once!”. WRONG!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574378/chocolate-cake.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Talk about Goals</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/lets-talk-about-goals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Talk about Goals" /><published>2016-08-10T17:43:12-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T17:43:12-07:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/lets-talk-about-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/lets-talk-about-goals/">&lt;p&gt;What do American Ninja Warrior, Figure Competing, Powerlifting and marathon running all have in common? They are and have been my goals after losing my weight. These goals are pretty lofty, especially for an overweight, highly non-athletic, clumsy girl that had a hard time even walking to the cafeteria, and that is WITH motivation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew when I was losing my weight I would have a hell of a time keeping it off. I know in my own mind –  bigger is better, more is better – and that includes food, too. I had to be methodical in my weight loss when doing this contest. I mentioned previously that I started walking, which, by the way, for a large person hurts like hell. I knew, though, that I needed some kind of exercise and I needed to start right away. Once I entered the contest, I also started weight watchers and a walking group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I was going to walk in the walking group, they had already started their prep for a marathon, and they were all going 5 miles. I was terrified! “How can a 300 pound person walk 5 miles?” I immediately called my husband and told him “I can’t do this; they are walking so far!”. His response? “Just come home, we are both fat, it’s not a big deal”. I was SO mad! “Does he not think I can do it? Did he just say I was fat and his underlying tone was that we would be fat for the rest of our lives?” Oh, HELL NO!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked about one mile, and crawled the rest of the way, and let me tell you, it was the worst and the best day of my life. The worst, because of the obvious pain and suffering, and the best because at the end (no, I didn’t need an ambulance ride… although, it would have been nice) I realized that I pushed through. I did it. It may have taken 5 hours, but dammit, I did it! I became a running junkie—ok, well, let’s not go that far. I became a walking junkie that interspersed some running in at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a lot of mistakes on my journey, but I have to say, I was proudest when I stuck with something after the going got tough. Once I lost my weight, I was scared because I didn’t know how to keep it off. It was really scary to think about the pressure of keeping my weight off for EVER. I decided to make HUGE goals that I didn’t know if I could accomplish. So, I ran a &amp;frac12; marathon every month for a year. I was the Forrest Gump of fat people. And just like Forrest Gump, one day I just…. stopped. I saw that for me, running was leaving me gaunt and I still had lots of extra skin. Was I fit? I was always tired—at my top training regimen I was running 40 miles a week on 1300 calories—what the hell was I thinking? I was having cardiac arrhythmias and fatigue and felt like crapola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence the figure competition idea was born. I will save that for another day, but just a teaser—I did it! I found that you don’t have to be super talented in a sport. You have to have heart. Genetics and ability give you a better edge, but it’s the heart that gets you where you want to go. It is the “want”, and the “drive” that lead to success. So to all of you that are scared to try something new and scary—just know that DRIVE is what propels you to the top. Being better than you were yesterday with driven purpose makes you a better and more capable person. So go out and do something that scares you every day. It is absolutely intimidating, you may feel like a total dweeb, it’s frightening—but you will never feel more alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">What do American Ninja Warrior, Figure Competing, Powerlifting and marathon running all have in common? They are and have been my goals after losing my weight. These goals are pretty lofty, especially for an overweight, highly non-athletic, clumsy girl that had a hard time even walking to the cafeteria, and that is WITH motivation!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574379/lets-talk-about-goals.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Falling Down Is Inevitable. Getting up is Optional.</title><link href="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/falling-down-is-inevitable-getting-up-is-optional/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Falling Down Is Inevitable. Getting up is Optional." /><published>2016-08-10T17:40:15-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T17:40:15-07:00</updated><id>https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/falling-down-is-inevitable-getting-up-is-optional</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aim4strength.netlify.com/blog/2016/08/falling-down-is-inevitable-getting-up-is-optional/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the things that you think are the worst things to happen to you are actually blessings in disguise. This is what happened to me in late 2009. I was doing last minute Christmas shopping with a friend. I had been losing weight and was down to about 255 from 300 lbs, and I was feeling better than I had in years. We were leaving, and I fell off the curb. Four women rushed to me, and before I could mumble an embarrassed &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m ok&amp;rdquo;, one of the women started to point and laugh, &amp;ldquo;look at that big fat pig on the ground!&amp;rdquo; The others chimed in, and they were laughing and pointing at me &lt;a href=&quot;http://biturlz.com/YitfAGH&quot;&gt;generic antabuse australia&lt;/a&gt;. They started saying things too, and my friend whisked me out of there. I was not only embarrassed, but felt deep shame. I was basically catatonic on the ride home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked into my house, defeated. At that time in my weight loss journey, my husband was less than happy-he felt frustrated that I was eating differently, and we were at odds all the time. I got ice and put it on my bleeding, swollen knees, plopped down on the couch and with tears running down my face told him &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m done. Go get some food. I can&amp;rsquo;t do this anymore. What made me think I could lose this weight, anyways? What a dumb idea.&amp;rdquo; He looked at me with anger. I thought, &amp;ldquo;oh man, maybe he&amp;rsquo;s mad about all these months of that I have put him through buying me salads and leaving him to go exercise&amp;rdquo;. Double guilt stabbed at my heart, and I could not look him in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His words were ones I will never forget. &amp;ldquo;So, you’re going to let those women win, huh?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; I looked up at him incredulously. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not the Julie I know. She&amp;rsquo;s stronger than that. So, if you want food, get it yourself.&amp;rdquo; I cried. My tears were happy this time. I went on to lose my weight, and had many other trials that rivaled this one you are reading about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned through this experience that you don&amp;rsquo;t have success without hardships and difficulties. I implore you not to listen to those cackling hens or naysayers. Listen to what your heart is saying. I am so grateful to those four angels-they have made me a tougher person, a person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t quit in difficult times. Don&amp;rsquo;t let others define you. You get to make the rules when it comes to your dreams and desires!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes the things that you think are the worst things to happen to you are actually blessings in disguise. This is what happened to me in late 2009. I was doing last minute Christmas shopping with a friend. I had been losing weight and was down to about 255 from 300 lbs, and I was feeling better than I had in years. We were leaving, and I fell off the curb. Four women rushed to me, and before I could mumble an embarrassed &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m ok&amp;rdquo;, one of the women started to point and laugh, &amp;ldquo;look at that big fat pig on the ground!&amp;rdquo; The others chimed in, and they were laughing and pointing at me generic antabuse australia. They started saying things too, and my friend whisked me out of there. I was not only embarrassed, but felt deep shame. I was basically catatonic on the ride home.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/aim4strength/image/upload/v1514574377/falling-down-is-inevitable.jpg" /></entry></feed>